# **Luiz Barros**

Rua Justiniano nunes da silva 675 • luizbarro 9782@gmail.com

# Web developer

7 years of web development experience. Implemented responsive design principles to ensure mobile compatibility of websites and maintained databases such as MySQL or Mongo. In 8 months improved and maintained web apps using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React and Next.js. This process increased number of 5-star UX/UI reviews by 135%

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Brazil | SAP Brazil LTDA •** 09/2022 - 03/2024

#### **Senior Web Developer**

- · Implemented responsive design principles to ensure mobile compatibility of 3 websites in 4 months.
- Communicated project status to primary stakeholders and project management personnel for 2 projects in 3 months.
- · Completed programming projects that complied with existing coding standards and design styles and improved user satisfaction by 37%.
- · Developed web platform that increased user conversion rate by 25% in 3 months.

# **Brazil | DevMagic •** 10/2020 - 03/2022

### **Web Developer**

- · Maintained databases such as MySQL or Mongo for storing dynamic data used by 3 websites and increased the performance by 31%.
- · Maintained understanding of current web technologies and programming practices through continuing education and participation in professional conferences and workshops in 5 months.
- · Developed and maintained web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.

# **Brazil | FUNORTE •** 05/2017 - 09/2020

#### **Jufiior Web Developer**

- Developed wireframes, site maps and content inventories for new website designs increase target audience engagement by 14% in 4 months.
- · Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability. Built website interfaces with HTML and CSS for 3 websites.
- · Spearheaded the development of dynamic web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React; increased user engagement by 25% boost in customer retention.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Federal University of Pernambuco**

Brazil • 2014 - 2017

#### **SKILLS**

React, Next.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript